Phillip: In this video we are going
to explain the benefits of innovation
and change for an organization.
Maddy: Change is a fact of life and
organisations at the forefront of their
industry or line of service won’t stay
that way if they can’t adapt to change.
Phillip: Innovation is when an organization
or business makes positive changes to
maintain its competitive edge and continue
to deliver quality products or services.
Maddy: It’s important that organisations
and businesses embrace the fact that they
need to change and innovate, as the world
around them is constantly moving, and it’s
necessary to innovate and change to keep pace.
If not, they’ll find themselves falling behind.
Phillip: Let’s look at some of the benefits
that can come from an organization or
business undergoing change and innovation.
Maddy: Embracing new technology
Every day, new technologies are being
invented or developed and new scientific
discoveries are being announced.
Although sometimes it can take a while
for an important new kind of technology
to establish itself, many organisations
and businesses keep an eye out for the
next game-changing technological advance.
By embracing new technology through innovation
and change, businesses and other organisations
can outcompete their rivals and satisfy
their customers’ needs more efficiently.
Phillip: Cost savings
By changing and innovating, organisations can
keep down costs especially through adopting
new work or management practices where
inefficiencies are identified and removed.
However sometimes this can involve
redundancies, not always a popular
change, especially when certain job
roles are found to no longer be needed.
Maddy: Increased profits
This is the flipside of cost savings.
By innovating and adapting, businesses and
organisations can increase the profits they’re
bringing in, which they can in tur, re-invest
into the business and reward their people.
Phillip: Boosting efficiency
Innovation can help an organization or
business discover more efficient ways
to deliver its product and services.
This can also help improve the customer
experience, making it more likely current
customers will stay loyal and spread
the good word about their experience.
It also frees up time and resources for
the organization to achieve even more.
Maddy: Competitiveness
For businesses, it’s always important to be as
competitive as possible, striving to do better
than other businesses in their field or industry.
Innovation is very important
in staying competitive.
If you’re not innovating, you can always
guarantee that one of your competitors is.
This is also true of non-business
organisations who want to maintain a
good reputation and continue to deliver
their services and products effectively.
Phillip: Willingness to experiment
It’s true that not all innovations and
changes achieve what they set out too.
But by embracing innovation and change, and
recognizing that they’re inevitable parts of
life, you can inspire a spirit of experimentation
in your people, making them more open minded
and more willing to try new ideas in the future.